1;1;{"question":"Which nation won the inaugural World Cup in 1930?", "rightAnswer":"Uruguay", wrongAnswer: ["Brazil","Italy","Argentina"], "answerText":"Uruguay won the inaugural World Cup in 1930.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (argentin*/italy/italian*/brazil*/(no/not/or) * uruguay*) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* uruguay* *"]}
2;2;{"question":"Who, in 1934, became the first African nation to play at a World Cup?", "rightAnswer":"Egypt", wrongAnswer: ["Morocco","Cameroon","Ghana"], "answerText":"Egypt became the first African nation to play at a World Cup.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (ghana*/cameroon*/morocc*/(no/not/or) * egypt*) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* egypt* *"]}
3;3;{"question":"In 1938, which nation became the first to win the World Cup for a second time?", "rightAnswer":"Italy", wrongAnswer: ["Brazil","Uruguay","Germany"], "answerText":"Italy became the first to win the World Cup for a second time.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (brazil*/uruguay*/german*/(no/not/or) * (italy/italian*)) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (italy/italian*) *"]}
4;4;{"question":"The 1950 World Cup was the first to ... ?", "rightAnswer":"Not have a World Cup Final", wrongAnswer: ["Feature an Asian nation","Be played in South America","Feature 16 competing nations"], "answerText":"The 1950 World Cup was the first to not have a World Cup Final.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* ([feature*] * asian [nation]/south * america/(16/sixteen) [compet*] (nation*/countr*)/(no/not/or) * not * ([world cup] final*)) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* not * ([world cup] final*) *"]}
5;5;{"question":"Which nation scored the most goals at the 1954 World Cup?", "rightAnswer":"Hungary", wrongAnswer: ["Brazil","England","Italy"], "answerText":"Hungary scored the most goals at the 1954 World Cup.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":[" * (italy/italian*/england/english*/britain/kingdom/brazil*/(no/not/or) * hungar*) * "], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* hungar* *"]}
6;6;{"question":"How old was Pele when he made his World Cup debut for Brazil in 1958?", "rightAnswer":"17 years old", wrongAnswer: ["16 years old","18 years old","19 years old"], "answerText":"Pele was 17 years old when he made his World Cup.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (16/18/19/sixteen*/eighteen*/nineteen*/(no/not/or) * (17/seventeen*)) [years [old]/y o] * "], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (17/seventeen*) [years [old]/age] *"], "answerIsNumber":"17"}
7;7;{"question":"The 1962 World Cup in Chile was the first to use what system as the primary means of separating two teams on the same amount of points?", "rightAnswer":"Goal average", wrongAnswer: ["Goal difference","Penalty shoot-out","Drawing of straws"], "answerText":"", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (goal* differ*/penalt* shoot*/draw* * straw*/(no/not/or) * {goal * average}) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* {goal * average} *"]}
8;8;{"question":"For how many days did the Jules Rimet trophy famously go missing for before the 1966 World Cup in England?", "rightAnswer":"7 days", wrongAnswer: ["30 days","4 days","21 days"], "answerText":"", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (30/4/21/thirty/twenty */four/(no/not/or) * (seven/7/week)) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (seven/7/week) [days]  *"], "answerIsNumber":"7"}
9;9;{"question":"Who won the Golden Boot at the 1970 World Cup?", "rightAnswer":"Gerd Muller", wrongAnswer: ["Jairzinho","Bobby Charlton","Pele"], "answerText":"Gerd Muller won the Golden Boot at the 1970 World Cup.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (jairzinho/[bobby] charlton/bobby [charlton]/pele/(no/not/or) * ([gerd] (muller/muler)*/gerd)) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* ([gerd] (muller/muler)*/gerd) *"]}
10;10;{"question":"The 1974 World Cup took place in which country?", "rightAnswer":"West Germany", wrongAnswer: ["Italy","Spain","France"], "answerText":"The 1974 World Cup took place in West Germany.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (italy/italian*/spain/spanish/franc*/(no/not/or) * [west] german*) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* [west] german* *"]}
11;11;{"question":"How old was legendary goalkeeper, Dino Zoff, when he won the World cup with Italy in 1982?", "rightAnswer":"40 years old", wrongAnswer: ["36 years old","38 years old","42 years old"], "answerText":"", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (36/38/42/thirty (six/eight)/fourty two/(no/not/or) * (40/fourt*)) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (40/fourt*) *"], "answerIsNumber":"40"}
12;12;{"question":"In Italia 1990, who became the first player to ever be sent off in a World Cup Final?", "rightAnswer":"Pedro Monzon", wrongAnswer: ["Diego Maradona","Roberto Baggio","Lothar Matthaus"], "answerText":"", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* ({[diego] maradona}/diego/{[roberto] baggio}/roberto/{[lothar] matthaus}/mathaus/lothar/(no/not/or) * ([pedro] monzon/{pedro [monzon]})) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (monzon/{pedro [monzon]}) *"]}
13;13;{"question":"Who scored a World Cup record of five goals in one game against Cameroon in USA 1994?", "rightAnswer":"Oleg Salenko", wrongAnswer: ["Hristo Stoichkov","Romario","Roberto Baggio"], "answerText":"", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* ( {[hristo] stoichkov}/hristo |romario| {[roberto] baggio}/roberto | (no/not/or) * ({[oleg] salenko}/oleg)) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* ({[oleg] salenko}/oleg) *"]}
14;14;{"question":"France 1998 was the first World Cup to feature â€¦ what?", "rightAnswer":"32 teams", wrongAnswer: ["Teams from every Fifa confederation","Three points for a group stage win","A third/fourth place playoff"], "answerText":"France 1998 was the first World Cup to feature 32 teams.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* ([fifa* *] confederation*/group stage/(three/3) point*/playoff/(no/not/or) * (32/thirty two) [teams]) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (32/thirty two) [teams] *"]}
15;15;{"question":"Who won the Golden Ball award for best player at the 2002 World Cup held in Japan/South Korea?", "rightAnswer":"Oliver Kahn", wrongAnswer: ["Michael Ballack","Ronaldo","Cafu"], "answerText":"Oliver Kahn won the Golden Ball award for best player at the 2002 World Cup.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* ({[michael] ballack}/michael/ronaldo/cafu/(no/not/or) * ({[oliver] kahn}/oliver)) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* ({[oliver] kahn}/oliver) *"]}
16;16;{"question":"Referee brandished 16 yellow cards and 4 reds in the round of 16 game dubbed \"The Battle of Nuremberg\" between which two nations at the 2006 World Cup?", "rightAnswer":"Portugal and Netherlands", wrongAnswer: ["Germany and Portugal","Spain and France","Netherlands and Germany"], "answerText":"", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* ({german* * portuga*}/{(spain*/spanish) * franc*}/{(netherland*/dutch) * german*}/(no/not/or) * {portugal* * (netherlands/holland)} ) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* {portugal* * (netherlands/holland)} *"]}
17;17;{"question":"Who were the only nation to remain unbeaten throughout the 2010 World Cup?", "rightAnswer":"New Zealand", wrongAnswer: ["Spain","Slovakia","Germany"], "answerText":"New Zealand were the only nation to remain unbeaten throughout the 2010 World Cup.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (spain/spanish/slovak*/german*/(no/not/or) * [new] zealand) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* [new] zealand *"]}
18;18;{"question":"Who won the world cup in 2014?", "rightAnswer":"Germany", wrongAnswer: ["Argentina","Spain","France"], "answerText":"Germany won the world cup in 2014", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (argentin*/spain/spanish/franc*/(no/not/or) * german*) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* german* *"]}
19;19;{"question":"Who won the world cup in 2010?", "rightAnswer":"Spain", wrongAnswer: ["Netherlands","Germany","Brazil"], "answerText":"Spain won the world cup in 2010", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (netherland*/dutch/brasil*/franc*/(no/not/or) * (spain/spanish)) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (spain/spanish) *"]}
20;20;{"question":"Who won the world cup in 2006?", "rightAnswer":"Italy", wrongAnswer: ["France","Germany","Brazil"], "answerText":"Italy won the world cup in 2006", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (franc*/german*/brazi*/(no/not/or) * (italy/italian*)) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (italy/italian*) *"]}
21;21;{"question":"Who won the world cup in 2002?", "rightAnswer":"Brazil", wrongAnswer: ["Italy","Argentina","Germany"], "answerText":"Brazil won the world cup in 2002", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (ital*/argentin*/german*/(no/not/or) * brazil* ) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* brazil* *"]}
22;22;{"question":"Who won the world cup in 1998?", "rightAnswer":"France", wrongAnswer: ["Italy","Brazil","Germany"], "answerText":"France won the world cup in 1998", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (ital*/brazi*/german*/(no/not/or) * franc* ) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* franc* *"]}
23;23;{"question":"Who won the world cup in 1994?", "rightAnswer":"Brazil", wrongAnswer: ["Italy","Argentina","Germany"], "answerText":"Brazil won the world cup in 1994", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (ital*/argentin*/german*/(no/not/or) * brasil* ) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* brasil* *"]}
24;24;{"question":"Who won the world cup in 1990?", "rightAnswer":"Germany", wrongAnswer: ["Brazil","Argentina","Netherlands"], "answerText":"Germany won the world cup in 1990", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (brazi*/argentin*/netherland*/dutch/(no/not/or) * german* ) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* german* *"]}
25;25;{"question":"Which country hosted the 1994 world championship?", "rightAnswer":"USA", wrongAnswer: ["Mexico","Netherlands","Argentina"], "answerText":"USA hosted the 1994 world championship.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (mexic*/netherland*/dutch/argentin*/(no/not/or) * (usa/america*/state*) ) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (usa/america*/state*) *"]}
26;26;{"question":"How many world cups did Brazil win?", "rightAnswer":"5 world cups", wrongAnswer: ["2 world cups","3 world cups","4 world cups"], "answerText":"Brazil have won 5 world cups.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (2/3/4/two/second/three/third/four*/(no/not/or) * (five/5) ) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (five/5) *"], "answerIsNumber":"5"}
27;27;{"question":"How many world cups did Germany win?", "rightAnswer":"4 world cups", wrongAnswer: ["2 world cups","3 world cups","5 world cups"], "answerText":"", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (2/3/5/two/second/three/third/five/(no/not/or) * (4/four)) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (4/four) *"], "answerIsNumber":"4"}
28;28;{"question":"How many world cups finals did Germany play?", "rightAnswer":"8", wrongAnswer: ["5","7","9"], "answerText":"Germany become the first team to reach 8 World Cup Finals.", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* (5/7/9/five*/seven*/nine/ninth/(no/not/or) * (eight*/8)) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (eight*/8) *"], "answerIsNumber":"8"}
29;29;{"question":"Which player scored most goals in a single world cup tournament?", "rightAnswer":"Just Fontaine", wrongAnswer: ["Miraslov Klose","Ronaldo","Pele"], "answerText":"", "wrongAnswerPatterns":["* ({[miraslov] klose}/miraslov/ronaldo/pele/(no/not/or) * (just [justo] fontaine/just*/{[just] fontaine})) *"], "rightAnswerPatterns":["* (just [justo] fontaine/just*/{[just] fontaine}) *"]}